Guide to the Coordinating Board, Texas College and University System Records 1985-002
University of Houston Libraries Special Collections
Coordinating Board, Texas College and University System Records
1965-1985
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Coordinating Board, Texas College and University System
1985-002
3.00 Linear Feet
This collection arrived at the archives in relatively good order, which has been maintained where possible. The collection consists of Audit Reports, Correspondence, Board Minutes, Proposals, Reports, Rules and Regulations, Resolutions, and Statements.
Historical Note:
The Coordinating Board, Texas College and University System, is a statutory board appointed by the Governor. It is responsible for statewide planning and policy-making to assure quality and efficiency in Texas higher education. The Board's primary areas of responsibility are financial planning, senior colleges and universities, community colleges, and continuing education, health affairs, student services and campus planning.
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
This collection arrived at the archives in relatively good order, which has been maintained where possible. The collection consists of Audit Reports, Correspondence, Board Minutes, Proposals, Reports, Rules and Regulations, Resolutions, and Statements.
Administrative records; Correspondence; Minutes; Reports; Coordinating Board, Texas College and University System; Texas Higher Education Coordinating Board; University of Houston
- Acts & Bills (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Agendas, 1968-1972, 1975, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Agenda Items (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Annual Report, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Annual Report, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Audit Report, August 31, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Audit Report, August 31, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Audit Report, August 31, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Audit Report, August 31, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Audit Report, August 31, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Audit Report, August 31, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bond Resolutions: Memo to Gresham, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Certificate: Newton Gresham, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Compliance Agreement (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Correspondence - Board Members, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Correspondence - J. K. Williams - Commissioner of Higher Education (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Financial Report, August 31, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Financial Report, August 31, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Financial Report, August 31, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Financial Report, August 31, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Financial Report, August 31, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Financial Report, August 31, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Formulas for Public Senior Colleges and Universities (Box 2, Folder 14)
- General Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- General Correspondence, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- General Correspondence, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- General Correspondence, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- General Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- General Correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- General Correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- General Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- General Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- General Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- General Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- General Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- General Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- General Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- General Correspondence, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- General Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- General Correspondence, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Guide for New Members (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Index of Minutes, September 1, 1969-August 31, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Index of Minutes, September 1, 1970-August 31, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Index of Minutes, September 1, 1971-August 31, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Index of Minutes, September 1, 1972-August 31, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Index of Minutes, September 1, 1973-August 31, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Minutes, October 17, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Minutes, February 9, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Miscellaneous Financial Info (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Miscellaneous Papers (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Miscellaneous Travel Info (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Miscellaneous Shorthand Notes (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Newspaper Articles/Clippings, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Newspaper Clippings - J.K. Williams (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Notes and Study Materials for Legal Education, November 22, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Pamphlets and Monthly Reports (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Presentation by the Dallas Chamber of Commerce (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Presentation Before Senate Finance Committee and House Appropriations Committee (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Proposal - Agricultural - Business Degree, July 18, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Proposal - Criteria for New Baccalaureate Degree Programs (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Proposal - Fiscal Regulations, July 19, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Proposal - Goals for the Expansion of Physical Facilities in Texas Public Higher Education (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Proposal - Outline for Developing Institutional Description and Projections (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Proposal - Research and Development Project, July 1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Proposal - State Commission (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Proposal - Texas Public Community/Junior College Association (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Public Hearings (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Recommendations, Suggestions and Tentative Outlines (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Report - Advisory Committee on Legal Education (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Report - Chrys Dougherty (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Report - Enrollment in the Music Area (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Report - Position Report on New Law School (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Report - Public Debt of the Public Senior Colleges and Universities and Medical Schools in the State of Texas (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Report - SHSH PhD Degree Program Request in Criminal Justice (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Report - State of Texas College Student Loan Program (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Report - The Status and Prospects of UTPB as an Upper Level Institution (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Report - Trends in State Funding in Higher Education (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Requests for Academic Programs and Administrative Changes (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Requests - Prairie View, TX - the Centennial Council (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Resolutions (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Rules and Regulation, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Staff Material (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Statements and Addresses (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Study - Health Science Library Resources in TX (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Study - Texas Formula System (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Study - The Availability and Use of Public Senior Higher Education Facilities in Texas, January 1980 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- West Texas Statutes and Codes (Box 3, Folder 35)